Guide to the Peter Wellington Alexander Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Peter Wellington Alexander Papers,
1855-1863,
Alexander, Peter Wellington, 1825-1886.
10 linear feet (18 document boxes and 12 flat boxes). 16 reels of microfilm (8 positive reels-2 copies of reels 1-3 & 5-7); 8 master negative reels).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, New York 10027.
MS#0016
4079103
History
Colonel Peter Wellington Alexander, Confederate States of America, Georgia-born editor and Civil War correspondent.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of over four hundred letters to Alexander, as well as miscellaneous letters and telegrams; business and military documents; and copybooks and letter books; and complete and partial newspapers and clippings from the various Southern newspapers with which he was affiliated, in particular The Savannah Republican and the Advertiser and Register of Mobile, which carried Alexander's dispatches.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into 5 series:
Cataloged Correspondence
Arranged Series
Correspondence
Telegrams
Manuscripts & Documents
Copybooks, Letterbooks, etc.
Miscellaneous Documents
Orders
Reports
Southern United States Newspspers
Printed Documents & Books
Addition (1976)
Subjects
Confederate States of America.--Army.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives.; Journalists.; Editors.
Acquisition
Microfilm
Guide to the materials on microfilm, 1 volume, in repository.
Selected Related Material
Community & Conflict: The Impact of the Civil War in the Ozarks
This online exhibition includes a large amount of dogitized material from the Columbia University Collection
- Cataloged Correspondence
  - Alexander, A[lmerine] M. To [Thomas C. Hindman]Camp on the White River 23 Oct. 1862, a.l.s., 2 p.; [On microfilm reels 90-2021 and 91-2089] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, A[lmerine] M. To R. C. Newton. [n.p.] 23 Oct. 1862., a.l.s., 2p.; [On microfilm reels 90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, George D. To Thomas C. Hindman. Little Rock, Ark. 15 Nov. 1862 and [n.d.], 2 a.l.s., 4 p.; [On microfilm reels 90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, George D. To R.C. Newton. Post Arkadelphia, Ark. 10 March 1863., a.l.s., 5 p.; [On microfilm reels 90-1021 and 91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, George S. (Alexanders' son) To Theresa Shorter Alexander. [near Columbua, GA] 1877., a.l.s., 2 p.; [Not on microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander Peter Wellington To [?]. Near Chattanooga 4 Oct. 1863., a.l.s., 3 p.; [Not on microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington Business and professional correspondence. [v.p.] 3 Aug. 1866-21 July 1886., 4 a.l.s., 1 p.l.s., with 5 encl.; [Not on microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To Mrs. Alexander. Columbus and Atlanta 27 March 1870-[13 Dec.] 1876., 4 a.l.s., 25 p.; [Not on microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To W.A. Little. Atlanta, GA, 1 Jan 1874., a.l.s., 1 p.; [Page from copybook. Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington Letters to Peter Wellington Alexander from various people. [v.p.] 10 Feb. 1876-2 Jan. 1884., 5 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington Letters from various persons. Marietta and Macon, 23 June 1876 -14 March 1881., 3 a.l.s., 1 p.c., 9 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To Mrs. Alexander. Marietta and Atlanta, 3 Jan. -2 Feb. 1977, 5 a.l.s., 15 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To Mrs. Alexander. Atlanta and Marietta, 31 March -29 Dec. 1877., 4 a.l.s., 16 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To Mrs. Alexander. Marietta, 7 Sept. 1878 -21 March 1879., 5 a.l.s., 17 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To Mrs. Alexander. Marietta and Atlanta, 9 July 1880 -24 March [1881], 4 a.l.s., 11 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To Mrs. Alexander. Marietta and Macon, 1 April 1881 -5 June 1884., 4 a.l.s., 12 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To his daughter, Sallie, and his neice [Lizzie?]. Marietta and Atlanta 16 Feb. 1877 -27 March 1881., 4 a.l.s., 12 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To Joseph Emerson Brown (1821-1894). Macon, Ga. 25 Jan. 1884., a.l.s., 1 p. (draft).; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Peter Wellington To James Milton Smith (1823-1890). Marietta, Ga. 20 April 1886., a.l.s., 5 p. (copy).; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Sallie S. (Alexanders' daughter) To Peter Wellington Alexander. [near Columbua, GA] 9 -20 Dec. 1876., 2 a.l.s., 3 p.; encl.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) Letters to Mrs. Alexander in sympathy on the death of her husband. [v.p.] 22 Sept-12 Nov. 1886., 25 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) Letters to Mrs. Alexander from friends. Columbus, Ga., and Hardaway, Ala. 3 April 1862-24 Oct. 1863., 3 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) To Mr. Lurman. Columbus, Ga. 30 May 1861., a.l.s., 8 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) To Mrs. Alexander from various persons. [v.p.] 28 Aug. [1870] -29 March 1887., 3 a.l.s., 10 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) To Mrs. Alexander from family. [v.p.] 21 Feb. 1871 -[ca. 9 Aug. 1918]., 5 a.l.s., 21 p.; ms. 3 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) To Peter Wellington Alexander. [v.p.] 11 March [1874] -13 Dec. 1876., 6 a.l.s., 26 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) To Peter Wellington Alexander. [Columbus, GA] 1 Feb. 1877 -15 Feb. 1879., 8 a.l.s., 34 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) To Mrs. Alexander from her family. [v.p.] 24 Aug. 1881-13 Oct 1886., 7 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington) To Sallie S. Alexander. Columbus, GA 10 May 1890., 1 a.l.s., 9 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Beauregard, Pierre Gustave Toutant To Peter Wellington Alexander. New Orleans, LA 6 Nov 1886., a.l.s., 1 p.; [Microfilm Reel 94-2007-2.] (Box 1)
  - Beauregard, Pierre Gustave Toutant To Col. Alexander. New Orleans, LA 2 May 1886., a.l.s., 2 p. (copy); [Encl. with above. Microfilm Reel 94-2007-2.] (Box 1)
  - Beckwith, John Watrous To [Peter Wellington Alexander]. Augusta, Ga. 11 Dec. 1874., a.l.s., 2 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Beckwith, John Watrous To Peter Wellington Alexander. New York 25 May 1875, a.l.s., 4 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Benham, Calhoun To Peter Wellington Alexander. Tunnel Hill, Ga. 21 Dec 1863., a.l.s., 1 p.; [Encl, 14 a.p.: biographical sketch of Patrick Ronayne Cleburn. Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Blunt, James Gilpatrick To Thomas C. Hindman. In the field 8 Dec. 1862., 2 a.l.s., 2 p.; [On exchanging prisioners after the Battle of Prairie Grove. Microfilm 90-2021 and91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Blunt, James Gilpatrick To Thomas C. Hindman. Rays Mill, Ark. 17 Dec. 1862, a.l.s., 2 p.; [Microfilm 90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Boudinot, Elias Cornelius To [Thomas C. Hindman]. Camp on Grand River, C.N. [Okla.] 16 June 1862., a.l.s., 2 p.; [Microfilm 11568.] (Box 1)
  - Boudinot, Elias Cornelius To [Thomas C. Hindman]. Cane Hill, Ark. 7 Dec. 1862., a.l.s., 2 p.; [Microfilm 11568.] (Box 1)
  - Bragg, Braxton To Jefferson David. Missionary Ridge, Tenn. 16 Nov. 1863., ms.l., 3 p. (copy); [Enclosed with Robias Gibson Richardson's letter of 8 Nov. 1864.] (Box 2)
  - Bragg, Braxton To Peter Wellington Alexander. Near Lowndesboro, Ala. 10 Dec. 1865., a.l.s., 3 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Bragg, Braxton To [?] [n.p.] 21 Feb. 1866, a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Brown, Joseph Emerson To Peter Wellington Alexander. Washington 17 Jan. -28 Feb. 1884., 1 a.l.s., 1 t.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Bullock, Rufus B. To Peter Wellington Alexander. Atlanta 2 Jan. 1884., 1 a.l.s., 1 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Burbridge, John Q. To R. C. Newton. [v.p.] 2-29 Oct. 1862., 3 a.l.s., 5 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Burbridge, John Q. To Thomas C. Hindman. Yellville, Ark. 10 Nov. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 2 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Burbridge, John Q. To R. C. Newton. Camp Near Wild Haus, Mo. 28-30 Nov. 1862., 3 a.l.s., 5 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Carroll, Charles A. To Thomas C. Hindman. Fort Smith, Ark 19 July -12 Aug. 1862., 2 a.l.s., 3 ms.l.s., 12 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Carroll, Charles A. To Thomas C. Hindman. Camp Mt. Comfort, Arks and [v.p.] 27 Aug. -1 Nov. 1862., 9 a.l.s., 9 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Carroll, Charles A. To Col. R. C. Newton. [v.p.] 8 Aug. -2 Nov.1862, 3 a.l.s., 4 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Carroll, Charles A. To Col. M. L. Young. [n.p.] [n.d.]., a.l.s., 1p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Clark, John Bullock To Thomas C. Hindman. Richmond, VA 12 Aug. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 3 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Clark, John Bullock To Thomas C. Hindman. Fort Smith, Ark. 18 Nov. -21 Dec.1862., 7 a.l.s., 7 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Douglas H. To various persons. Fort Davis and Scullyville, [Okla.] 28 July -24 Dec. 1862., 6 a.l.s., 6 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Douglas H. To Thomas C. Hindman. Fort Davis, etc. 29 July -24 Nov. 1862., 8 a.l.s., 12 p., 1 a.p. encl.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Douglas H. To Thomas C. Hindman. Scullyville 2 -19 Dec.1862., 6 a.l.s., 8 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Douglas H. To Col. R. C. Newton. Scullyville, etc. 28 Oct. -19 Dec.1862., 12 a.l.s., 18 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Douglas H. To John Selden Roane. Scullyville 14 Nov. -26 Dec.1862., 6 a.l.s., 7 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Curtis, Samuel Ryan To Thomas C. Hindman. St. Louis 10 Oct. 1862., ms.l.s., 2 p.; [Microfilm Reel 90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Davis, Jefferson To [?]. [n.p.] [n.d.], 1 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Dawson, William Crosby To Peter Wellington Alexander. Greensboro, GA 20 Sept. 1855., 1 a.l.s., 3 p.; [Microfilm Reel 90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Dunnington, John W. To Thomas C. Hindman. Little Rock, Ark. 21 June 1862., 1 a.l.s., 5 p.; [Encl sketch of St. Charles on the White River (setting of the Battle of St Charles, whichis described in this letter). Microfilm Reel 90-2021 and 91-2089:] (Box 1)
  - Dunnington, John W. To Charles A. Nelson. Little Rock, Ark. 3 Sept. 1862., ms.l.s., 1 p. (copy).; [With covering a.n.s. from Charles C. Green to Gen. J. P. Wilson. Microfilm Reel90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Egan, James S. To Peter Wellington Alexander. New Orleans 11 Dec. 1865., 1 a.l.s., 2p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Fagan, James Fleming To Col. R. C. Newton et al. [v.p.] 27 Nov. -28 Dec. 1862., 5 a.l.s., 6 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Folsom, Peter To Thomas C. Hindman and Douglas H. Cooper. Scullyville [Okla.] 10 July -20 Nov. 1862., 3 a.l.s., 2 ms.l., 13 p.; with 1 encl.; [Microfilm Reel 90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 1)
  - Frost, Daniel Marsh To Col. R. C. Newton. Hq. 3rd Div., Trans. Miss. Army 22 Nov. -30 Dec.1862., 10 a.l.s., 1 ms.l.s., 19 p.; with encl.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 1)
  - Gwin, William McKendree To William McKendree Gwinn, Jr. New York 5 July 1876., 1 a.l.s., 1 p.; [Introducing Peter Wellington Alexander. Not on Microfilm.] (Box 1)
  - Hardee, William Joseph To Peter Wellington Alexander. Hermitage, Ala. 11 Jan. 1866., 1 a.l.s., 4 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Harris, Samuel Smith To Peter Wellington Alexander. New Orleans 24 Nov. 1874., 1 a.l.s., 2 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Hayes, Major and Q. M. W. H. To Col. R. C. Newton et al. Fort Smith, Ark. 25 Oct. -23 Dec. 1862., 5 a.l.s., 6 ms.l.s., 14 p.; [Microfilm Reel 90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Herron, Francis Jay To Thomas C. Hindman. In the field [Prairie Grove, Ark.] 8 Dec. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 1 p.; [Microfilm Reel 90-2021 and 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Hill, Benjamin Harvey To Peter Wellington Alexander. Washington 26 Jan. 1876., 1 a.l.s., 3 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Hill, Daniel Harvey To Generals Cooper, Johnston, and Marshall. Chattanooga, Tenn. 6 -22 Aug. 1863 and [n.d.], 5 a.n.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Hindman, Thomas Carmichael To various persons. Little Rock, Ark., etc. 14 -17 Jan. 1863., 1 a.l.s. (draft); 1 a.l.; 1 ms.l.s.l 4 ms.l., 8 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Holmes, Theophilus Hunter To Thomas C. Hindman. Little Rock, Ark. 18 Aug. 1862., a.l.s., 2 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Holmes, Theophilus Hunter To Col. R. C. Newton. Camp on Horsehead, Ark. 6 Nov. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 2p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Holmes, Theophilus Hunter To Thomas C. Hindman. Little Rock, Ark. 27 Aug. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 3 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Holmes, Theophilus Hunter To Thomas C. Hindman. Little Rock, Ark. 4 Sept.1862., 1 a.l.s., 2 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Hunter, R. W. To [Peter Wellington Alexander]. [Near Cedar Creek, VA] 27 Oct. 1864., 1 a.l.s., 2 p.; [Envelope encl with postage stamp of the Confederate States of America. Not onMicrofilm.] (Box 2)
  - Jackson, Henry Rootes To [Peter Wellington Alexander]. Savannah, GA 23 March1865., 1 a.l.s., 1 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Jenkins, Charles Jones To Joseph Ganahl. Bedford Springs and Newport, VA 6 -23 Sept. 1880., 2 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Johnston, Joseph Eggleston To Peter Wellington Alexander. Abingdon, VA 17 Oct. 1865., 1 a.l.s., 1p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Jones, B. F. To Braxton Gragg. Mobile, Ala. 10 Oct 1864., 1 a.l.s., 4 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Lanigan, Thomas To Col. R. C. Newton. Fort Smith, Ark. 1 Oct. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 3 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box >2)
  - Lanigan, Thomas To Major N. S. Hill. Camp near Fort Smith 27 Nov. 1863., 1 a.l.s., 4 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Lawton, Alexander Robert To Peter Wellington Alexander. Savannah, GA 19 July 1866., 1 a.l.s., 17 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Lawton, Alexander Robert To [Peter Wellington Alexander]. Savannah, GA 9 Oct. 1866., 1 a.l.s., 3 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Lawton, Alexander Robert To John Cabell Breckinridge. Richmond, VA 10 March 1865., 1 ms.l.s., 9 p. (copy); [Enclosed with above. Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Lee, Robert Edward To Peter Wellington Alexander. Lexington, VA 11 Oct. 1865., 1 a.l.s., 2 p.; [Microfilm Reel 94-2007-2.] (Box 2)
  - Lee, Robert Edward To Theophilus Hunter Holmes. Richmond, VA 12 Sept. 1862., Telegram, 2p.; [Forwarded to Gen. Holmes by S. Cooper. Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Leslie, R. To Peter Wellington Alexander. Troup Factory [La Grange], GA 13 Jan. 1866., 1 a.l.s., 3p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Longstreet, James To Peter Wellington Alexander. Gainesville, GA 26 Nov. 1865., 1 a.l.s., 2p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - McLaws, Lafayette To Peter Wellington Alexander. Augusta, GA 5 Dec. 1865., 1 a.l.s., 1p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - McRae, Duncan Kirkland To Col. R. C. Newton. Camp on Mulberry Mt., Ark. 21 Oct. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 1p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - McRae, Duncan Kirkland To [Col. R. C. Newton?] Little Rock, Ark. 17 Feb. 1863., 1 a.l.s., 5p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - McDonald, Emmett To Thomas C. Hindman, et al. Pinesville, Mo. and [v.p.] 1 Sept. -24 Dec. 1862., 9 a.l.s., 21 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Marmaduke, John Sappington To Thomas C. Hindman et al. [v.p.] 5 Nov. -1 Dec. 1862., 7 a.l.s., 15 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Marmaduke, John Sappington To Col. R. C. Newton. [v.p.] 23 -29 Oct. 1862., 11 a.l.s., 7 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Marmaduke, John Sappington To Col. R. C. Newton. Van Buren, Ark. 1 -7 Nov.1862, 7 a.l.s., 3 ms.l., 16 p.; with encl.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Marmaduke, John Sappington To Col. R. C. Newton. [v.p.] 17 -28 Nov.1862., 10 a.l.s., 16 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Marmaduke, John Sappington To Col. R. C. Newton. [v.p.] 2 -24 Dec.1862., 6 a.l.s., 2 ms.l.s. 13 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Marmaduke, John Sappington To [?]. [n.p.] 20 Dec. 1862., 1 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Mayers, Capt. A. G. To Douglas H. Cooper and Gen. N. B. Pearce. Fort Washita [Okla.] 1 Sept. -1 Dec. 1862., 6 a.l.s., 12 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Mayers, Capt. A. G. To Thomas C. Hindman. Fort Washita [Okla.] 1 Sept. -3 Dec. 1862, 10 a.l.s., 16 p.; with 6 encl., 9 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Newton, Col. R. C. To [various persons]. [v.p.] 4 Sept. -18 Nov. 1862., 5 a.l.s., 10 p.; with 2 encl.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Parsons, Musby Monroe To Thomas C. Hindman. Yellville, Ark. and [v.p.] 27 Sept. -25 Oct.1862., 7 a.l.s., 1 ms.l.s., 18 p..; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Parsons, Musby Monroe To Thomas C. Hindman. [v.p.] 27 Sept. -25 Oct.1862, 7 a.l.s., 1 ms.l.s., 18 p..; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Parsons, Musby Monroe To Thomas C. Hindman. [v.p.] 29 Oct. 9 Nov. 1862., 7 a.l.s., 9 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Parsons, Musby Monroe To [various persons]. [v.p.] 15 Oct. 1862 -21 Feb. 1863., 2 a.l.s., 4 ms.l.s., 10 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Pearce, Nicholas Bartlett To [various persons]. Fort Smith, Ark. 1 July -9 Sept. 1862., 5 a.l.s., 13 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Pike, Albert To Thomas C. Hindman. Fort. McCulloch [Okla.] 8 June 1862., ms.l., 15 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Raines, James S. To [various persons]. [v.p.] 17 Aug. -20 Oct. 1862., 7 a.l.s., 11p.; encl. 3 ms.p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - [Randolph, George Wythe] To General H. E. McCulloch. Richmond 25 Aug. 1862., 2 ms.l., 2, 3 p.; [Variant copies of the same letter not in the author's hand. Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Richardson, C. B. To Braxton Bragg. New York 23 Oct. 1865., 1 a.l.s., 4 p.; [A.n.s. by General Bragg on page 4. Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Richardson, Robias Gibson To Peter Wellington Alexander. Wilmington [N.C.] 8 Nov. 1964., 1 a.l.s., 1 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Richardson, Robias Gibson To Peter Wellington Alexander. Wilmington [N.C.] 8 Nov. 1964., 1 a.l.s., 1 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Roan, John Selden To Thomas C Hindman. Pine Bluff and Fort Smith, Ark. 26 June -13 Nov. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 3 ms.l.s., 4 ms.l., 15 p.; encl. 2 a.p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Roan, John Selden To Col. R. C. Newton. Fort Smith, Ark. 1 -30 Nov. 1862., 4 a.l.s., 8 ms.l.s., 14 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Sherman, William T. To [?]. [n.p.] 1862., 2 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Shorter, James Hargraves To [Peter Wellington Alexander] New York 5 Oct. 1874., 1 a.l.s., 8 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Shorter, James Hargraves To Peter Wellington Alexander. New York 9 Dec. 1876., 1 a.l.s., 4 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Shorter, James Hargraves To Theresa Shorter Alexander. New York 23 -[26] Sept. 1886., 2 a.l.s.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Shoup, Francis Asbury To Col. R. C. Newton and Thomas C. Hindman. [v.p.] 5 Nov. -14 Dec. 1862., 2 a.l.s., 6 ms.l.s., 1 ms.l., 9 p.; [Microfilm Reel 11568-2.] (Box 2)
  - Smith, James Milton To Peter Wellington Alexander. Columbus, GA 27 June 1879., 1 a.l.s., 4 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Sparks, James H. To Thomas C. Hindman and Col. R. C. Newton. Fort Smith, Ark. 16 Sept. -11 Nov. 1862., 8 a.l.s., 11 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Sparks, James H. To Thomas C. Hindman. Fort Smith, Ark. 19 Nov. 1862., 1 a.l.s., 1 p.; [Encl. a printed notice on the conscript law. Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Standish, Austin, M. To Col. R. C. Newton. [v.p.] 25 Oct. -17 Nov. 1862., 7 a.l.s., 10 p.; with 3 encl.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Stanford, F. A. To Theresa S. Alexander. McMinnville, Tenn. 1 May 1864., 1 a.l.s., 3 p.; [With 2 Confererate stamps.Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Stephens, Alexander Hamilton To Peter Wellington Alexander. Crawfordville, GA 29 Sept. 1855., 1 a.l.s., 4 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Totten, Joseph Gilbert To Thomas C. Hindman. Springfield, MO 17 Sept. 1862., 1 ms.l.s., 4 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Walker To William H. Seward. [n.p.] [n.d.]., a.l.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 3)
  - Watie, Stand To Douglas H. Cooper and Thomas C. Hindman. [v.p.] 28 June -25 Dec. 1862 and [n.d.]., 4 a.l.s., 9 p.; 1 encl.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Wilson, Major and A. A. Inspector Gen. J. P. To [various persons]. [v.p.] 5 July 1862 -8 Feb. 1863., 5 a.l.s., 2 ms.l., 10 p.; [Microfilm Reel 91-2089.] (Box 2)
  - Wilson, Major To Peter Wellington Alexander. Memphis, Tenn. 10 Nov. 1865., 1 a.l.s., 6 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
  - Wood, Fernando To Peter Wellington Alexander. Washington 27 Jan. 1875., 1 a.l.s., 1 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 2)
- Arranged Series
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, primarily of the commands of Generals Hindman and Holmes. Letters From: General Hindman R. C. Newton Charles W. Adams Charles A. Carroll John T. Coffee John H. Crump Fred Lear M. M. McBride D. Prodidence William Queensbury, et al. Letters To: General Hindman General Holmes R. C. Newton Douglas H. Cooper John H. Crump Daniel Marsh Frost John Sappington Marmaduke Musby Monroe Parsons James S. Rains J.P. Wilson, et al. [v.p.] 3 Jan. 1862 -Aug. 1863., 185 pieces.; [Microfilm Reel 90-2021.] (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous family correspondence. [v.p.] 1862-1906., One folder.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 13)
  - Telegrams
    - Confederate States of America. Army. Telegrams. [v.p.] June -Dec. 1862, 1,144 telegrams.; [Microfilm Reels 90-2022, 2023, 2024.] (Box 5 to 6)
    - Confederate States of America. Army. Telegrams. [v.p.] Aug. 1863., 64 telegrams.; [Microfilm Reels 90-2022, 2023, 2024.] (Box 6)
    - Confederate States of America. Army. Telegrams between Gens. Hindman and Holmes[v.p.] Dec. 1, 12, 1862., 110 telegrams.; [Microfilm Reels 90-2022, 2023, 2024.] (Box 6)
    - Confederate States of America. Army Undated telegrams[v.p.] [n.d.], 22 telegrams; 15 incomplete; [Microfilm Reels 90-2022, 2023, 2024.] (Box 6)
  - Manuscripts & Documents
    - Alexander, Peter Wellington Miscellaneous business papers. Atlanta 1 Oct. 1871 -17 Dec. 1886., 22 pieces.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 12)
    - Alexander, Peter Wellington The state of the Confederate cause. Macon, GA 17 May 1865., a.ms., 6 p.; [The events of the previous year and how they have brought on the catastrophe which hasovertaken the Confederate cause. Not on Microfilm.] (Box 3)
    - Alexander, Peter Wellington Diaries. Marietta, GA 9 March 1880 -23 Sept. 1886, a.ms., 7 volumes (4 vols.s.).; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 3)
    - Alexander, Peter Wellington Last will and testament, copy; with related letter from his lawyer, George Gantt. Marietta, GA 6 Oct. 1886., ms.d., 3 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 3)
    - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington Alexander) Biographical sketch of Col. Alexander. [n.p.] [ca. 1910]., a.ms., 3 p.; [Not on Microfilm.] (Box 3)
    - Alexander, Theresa Shorter (Mrs. Peter Wellington Alexander) Scrapbook. Columbus, GA March 1859., a.ms., 6 p.; [Newspaper clippings. The first page of the clippings that follows the pictures (mostly offamous people) has articles from the Montgomery Daily Advertiser of 1858 and [n.d.],signed by George H. Shorter as editor. The last, large proup of clippings is of the CivilWar. Not on Microfilm.] (Box 12)